Guide to the John Flannery and Company records, 1867-1912, bulk 1867-1892 RL.10027
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
John Flannery and Company records
1867-1912, bulk 1867-1892
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Flannery, John
RL.10027
15 Linear Feet
John Flannery and Company was a partnership of commission merchants, of Savannah, Ga. and was originally known as L. J. Guilmartin & Co. The records become those of John Flannery and Co. comprised of John L. Johnson and John Flannery after June 1877. This collection contains business papers of L. J. Guilmartin & Co., 1867-1877, and after 1877, of John Flannery and Co., cotton factors, commission merchants, and agents for several manufacturing concerns. Correspondence, principally with merchants and farmers in Georgia and Florida, concerns the purchase and sale of cotton, and to a lesser extent, other commodities, loans on crops, prices of cotton and other commodities, a government tax on cotton, 1867, and speculation in cotton.
Historical note
John Flannery and Company was a partnership of commission merchants, of Savannah, Ga. and was originally known as L. J. Guilmartin & Co. The records become those of John Flannery and Co. comprised of John L. Johnson and John Flannery after June 1877.
Collection Overview
This collection contains business papers of L. J. Guilmartin & Co., 1867-1877, and after 1877, of John Flannery and Co., cotton factors, commission merchants, and agents for several manufacturing concerns. Correspondence, principally with merchants and farmers in Georgia and Florida, concerns the purchase and sale of cotton, and to a lesser extent, other commodities, loans on crops, prices of cotton and other commodities, a government tax on cotton, 1867, and speculation in cotton. Also included are bills and receipts, deeds for land sold in Florida and Georgia, copies of insurance policies, and the report of a suit, 1860s, brought against L. J. Guilmartin & Co. Scattered letters refer to Reconstruction, bankruptcy laws in Georgia, and trading through the Grange. Persons mentioned include Edward W. Drummond, John Flannery, and Lawrence J. Guilmartin.
Provenance
The John Flannery and Company records were acquired by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library between 1951-1956.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Savannah (Ga.) -- Commerce; Georgia -- Commerce.; Merchants -- Georgia -- Savannah.; Commission merchants -- Georgia -- Savannah.; Fertilizer industry -- Southern States; Cotton trade -- Georgia; Merchants -- Correspondence; Reconstruction (U.S. history, 1865-1877); Georgia -- Economic conditions; Johnson, John L.; John Flannery and Company (Savannah, Ga.); Drummond, Edward W.; Guilmartin, Lawrence J.; L. J. Guilmartin and Company (Savannah, Ga.); Flannery, John
- John Flannery and Company records, 1867-1912, bulk 1867-1892
  - Correspondence, 1867 Feb 4 - 1871 Dec 12 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1871 Dec 13 - 1874 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1875 - 1876 Oct 26 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1876 Oct 27 - 1877 Jan 31 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1877 Feb 1 - 1877 Oct 23 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1877 Oct 24 - 1878 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, 1879 Jan - 1879 Nov 24 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1879 May 24 - 1880 May 29 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, 1880 Jun 1 - 1881 Aug 2 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, 1881 Aug 24 - 1882 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence, 1883 - 1884 Feb 29 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence, 1884 Mar 1 - 1885 Sept (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, 1885 Oct - 1886 May 11 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, 1886 May 12 - 1887 Jul 28 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, 1887 Aug 1 - 1888 Jul 30 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, 1888 Aug 1 - 1889 Jan 8 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, 1889 Jan 9 - Jul 19 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, 1889 Jul 20 - 1889 Nov (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, 1889 Dec - 1890 Nov (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, 1890 Dec - 1912 and undated (Box 20)
  - Bills and receipts, 1860s - 1870s (Box 21)
  - Bills and Receipts, 1880 - 1902 and undated (Box 22)
  - Canceled Checks, 1879 (Box 23)
  - Canceled Checks, 1880 - 1889 (Box 24)
  - Canceled Checks, 1868, 1877-1881 (Box 25)
  - Canceled Checks, 1878 - 1879 (Box 26)
  - Canceled Checks, 1894 - 1895 (Box 27)
  - Canceled Checks, 1894 - 1895 (Box 28)
  - Canceled Checks, 1894 - 1895 (Box 29)
  - Canceled Checks, 1894 - 1895 (Box 30)